# Taras Lelak

CONTACT

Al Engineer taraslelak5@gmail.com

Highly skilled AI Engineer with over **8+ years of experience** in developing Machine Learning Models, deep learning architecture. Strong problem-solving and analytical skills, with a passion for learning new technologies and keeping up with industry trends

#### **EDUCATION**

• Master of Computer Science, The National University of Ostroch Academy, 2011-2017

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming languages: Python2, Python3, Python, Java, JS/TS
- Frameworks: Django, FastAPI, LangChain, Swagger, Cypress, Jest,
- Libraries/API: TensorFlow, PyTorch, PySpark, NumPy, Pandas REST APIs, GraphQL APIs, OpenAI API
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB
- Platfroms: AWS(Instance, Cognito, bedrock, S3, Lambda), Azure, CrewAI, Livekit, Vapi, Deepgram, ElevenLabs
- **Tools/Paradigms**: Git, Jira, Confluence, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Jenkins, Webpack, BDD/TDD, Clean code architecture, Automated Testing, Agile Software Development,
- Other: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, AI, NLP, LLMs, Hugging face, LangChain, PineCone, Weaviate

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Al Engineer Dev.Pro Dec 2020 – Present

- Spearheaded the development of RAG application leveraging Weaviate(Vector DB), Azure OpenAI services, significantly optimizing performance and productivity
- Developed and deployed Manchine Learning models for predictive analysts, classification, and anomaly detection
- Designed and implemented an advanced AI-powered **Voice GPT application**, utilizing **LLM**(tts-model), **OpenAI** technologies, and the **Asterisk** framework, to enhance the banking customer service experience.
- Designed and implemented machine learning models for productions recommendation system

Leveraged knowledge in Python, Django, Azure, Aterisk, RAG system, Prompting, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Azure OpenAl service

#### Al Focused on Python developer

#### Axe software

Oct 2018 - Dec 2020

- Good understanding of Machine Learning such as supervised learning, Unsupervised learning, regression, and Classification
  Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, K Nearest Neighbor, Decision Tree, and Random Forest using Python Packages such as
  Scikit Learn, Pandas, NumPy, and Plotly
- Processed and analyzed large-scale datasets, using Numpy, Pandas, and Scipy for feature extraction and transformation
- Managed end-to-end software development lifecycle(SDLC), from planning and design to deployment and maintenance.
- Built data pipelines for prepossessing and feature engineering with Pandas and Scikit-learn
- Built and integrated API s with third-party services such as payment gateways and shipping providers.

Leveraged knowledge in MongoDB, GraphQL, Kafka, Pandas, Scikit-learn, SDLC, Numpy, Scipy, Deep learning

## **Python developer**

## **Mighty Digital**

Feb 2017 - Oct 2018

- Developed and maintained scalable Back end applications using Python and frameworks like Django, Flask, and FastAPI
- Built data-driven applications leveraging Python, Pandas, and Numpy for analytic and automation
- Leveraged AWS services such as EC2, S3 and Lambda to improve scalability of applications
- Automated software testing and deployment using Pytest, Jenkins, Docker for CI/CD
- Developed computer vision algorithms to aid in the local monitoring of the mosquito Aedes aegypti, an important disease vector.

<u>Leveraged knowledge</u> in Pytest, Jenkins, CI/CD, JavaScript, Docker, AWS, Azure, Numpy, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Pandas, NLP, Data visualization, MLOps, Computer vision

#### **CERTIFICATION**

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate